早晨。
主席。
所見嘅。
未能選出主席。
交付嘅事務。
亦都係處理大會。
影響立法會履行憲制嘅職能。
內會係立法會最重要嘅委員會。
我已經尋求咗資深大律師嘅意見。
但係今個會期發生嘅情況咧，係從未。
誒，各位就內會內務委員會。
佢係預備大會議程上嘅事項。
議會內咧係完成咗選舉，正負。
根據歷屆嘅經驗，內會都係一次。
亦都希望係盡快解決現時嘅困局。
內會自去年十月十五日開始選主席嘅程序。
嘅影響。
好遺憾。
我亦都注意到。
下而作出嘅。
選出正副主席。
到十月底都未能。
五號、六號、七號咧，開舉行特別會議。
使到立法會能夠正常運作。
而秘書處法律顧問喺十月咧已經詳細。
解釋未能選出主席，對內會運作。
議員放下政治，盡快完成內會嘅選舉。
當時嘅法律分析係基於內匯喺正常運作嘅情況。
內會主席李慧瓊曾經安排喺二月初。
我係一直密切留意事態嘅發生，亦都係多次公開呼籲。
去由去年十月至今年嘅年初咧，內會都未能夠選到主席。
亦預期內會一如以往咧，可以喺短時期內咧係完成主席嘅選舉。
內會主席。
但係都選舉唔到。
到本屆嘅。
去務求盡快選舉。
履行憲制嘅責任。
內會冇辦法正常運作。
我已經收到資深大律師嘅意見。
特別係審議法案同埋附屬法案。
因此，我喺三月底咧，透過秘書處。
所以係必須要尋求解決嘅方法。
第七十三條所述嘅多項職能。
令立法會係冇辦法履行基本法。
但係由於疫情嘅嚴峻咧，會議係最後被逼取消。
就如何解決內會嘅問題咧，係尋求外間資深大律師嘅法律意見。
立法會對依個新嘅問題，我作為主席有責任去確保立法會有效。
直至到疫情比較穩定嘅時候咧，現任內會主席喺三月十三日咧，在該行會議去選舉主席。
例如。
總括嚟講。
現任內會主席。
主持選舉。
喺新任主席尚未選出前。
外間資深大律師確認。
大家都要留意到，而家內會。
此外，現任嘅主席亦唔應該故意拖延。
只係召開會議去選舉主政。
亦都要謹慎考慮是否行使呢啲權力。
具有一般權力，以處理內會嘅事務。
但行使依啲權力係受到一定嘅規範。
由於現任主席係新任主席嘅選舉嘅候選人，所以佢係無。
新主席嘅選舉，令到自己可以繼續擔任新會期嘅主席。
主席喺去年十月到而家都係去審慎去行使佢嘅主席嘅權力。
喺呢方面，外間資深嘅大律師同秘書處早前提供嘅意見咧，係並冇分歧嘅。
同埋議案。
郭議員。
係選舉主席。
郭榮亨議員。
並不相符。
喺選舉主席時。
所採用嘅方法。
資深大律師係認為。
喺正常嘅情況之下。
包括立法會大樓保安嘅安排。
然後接處理其他嘅事項。
新會期嘅首要處理嘅事務。
與內會主席選舉相關嘅事項。
難以係睇到如何。
與主持選舉議員嘅職能。
讓內會內務委員會啊討論多項。
已經屆滿。
同埋權力。
管核嘅事宜。
同埋執行嘅長程。
現任內會主席。
李慧瓊議員係有責任。
內會係無法處理。
都認為喺目前嘅情況之下。
立法會行政管理委員會。
秘書處同埋外間嘅資深大律師。
同埋多項冇約束力嘅意外。
期間有過百條嘅附屬法例嘅審議期。
由於內會係超過六個月，仲未選出主席。
現時已經係積壓咗十四條法案，二十多項附屬法例。
秘書處亦都就此曾向主持選舉嘅議員表達相同嘅意見。
委任中審法院首席法官嘅決議案，同埋多份法案委員會嘅報告係需要審議。
係有權。
以認知嘅問題。
大律師嘅法律意見。
來會延續。
因此喺目前嘅情況下。
嚴重積壓嘅工作。
現任內會主席李慧瓊議員。
交畀內會所有委員參考。
秘書處已經移備背景資料。
我今早已將外間之心。
使到立法會恢復正常嘅運作。
由於社會都十分關注內會嘅情況。
去處理因選舉主席出現過度言。
特別係處理重要或急切嘅事務。
亦都係有責去召開會議，去處理。
我亦都希望內會係盡快解決現時嘅困局。
參與。
從的past experience。
I would like to say a few words in English.
提供傳媒同公眾人士。
以及資深大律師就內會言。
主席選舉所提供嘅意見嘅要點。
作為House Committee has yet to elect its chairman.
and this has impeded the proper exercise.
啊！ sought the advice from outside senior councils.
Considering matters referred by the council.
of the constitutional functions of the Legislative Council.
Housecom is the most important committee of the council.
Preparing for business on the agenda of the council and consult.
但什麼發生在會期是 unprecedented。
on the relevant issues with the view to resolving the current deadlock as early as possible.
Housecom can usually conclude the election of his chairman and deputy chairman in one meeting.
是。
In property.
The implication.
at early this year.
on the operation of Housecom.
pending the election of its chairman.
Housecom has begun the process of.
The election of chairman within a short time.
The legal analysis made at the time was based.
Therefore, it is anticipated that Housecom could complete.
election of the chairman since the fifteenth of October last year.
on the ordinary course of events envisaged by Housecom.
我有監察，和， developments closely， and make repeated appeals.
and still failed to elect its chairman and deputy chairman by the end of the month.
as early as October last year, the secretary's legal adviser had explained in details.
regretably, after quite some time since last October, Housecom has not yet been able to elect its chairman.
在face of this novel.
so that the council can resume normal functioning.
therefore in late March, I have sought through the secretariat.
urging members to put aside their political differences.
啊！所以 now we receive advice from outside senior councils.
The exercise of such power is subject to certain caveat.
但Housecom still could not have its chairman elected at that meeting.
and complete the election of the House Home Chairman as soon as possible.
problem to let go. It is incumbent on me.
When Albert Esof, the incumbent Housecom chairman, called another meeting on the 13th of March.
The legal advice from outside senior councils on how to resolve the issues relating to Hong Kong.
However, the meeting were cancelled due eventually due to the severe situation of the COVID-19 outbreak.
作為主席，來識別一個解決方案，所以確保議會可以履行其憲法上的職責，有效地。
In summary, pending the election of the new chairman, while the incumbent House Com chairman should have all the usual powers to conduct the business of House Com.
我 notice that the incumbent House Committee Chairman or the Honorary Starry Lee had arranged special meetings to speed up the election of the Chairman of the current session.
The failure of Housecom to function normally had rendered the council unable to properly perform its function, as stipulated in Article 73 of the Basic Law.
先喺康師傅。
電力公司。
as House Com chairman.
say that the way.
在普通嘅course of events。
他 allow House of Members to have.
The election of the Housecombe Chairman for the new sessions should be the first item of business.
Ahead of any business to be transacted in a new session.
The secretary has also expressed similar views to the presiding member.
and she or he should exercise caution as to whether to exercise the power.
matters under the purview of the Legislative Council Commission, as well as a number of non-binding motions.
discussed on a number of issues and motions covering the security arrangements and their implementation in.
In this regard, senior council's advice is no different from the provided from that provided by the secretary earlier.
在 senior council's view， it is difficult to see how such discussion could be relevant to the election of the house committee chairman.
Honourable Dennis Kwok has contacted the election of chairman is inconsistent with the powers and functions of the presiding member.
since October last year, the incumbent House Com Chairman had has prudently exercised power as the Chairman in office, only to call meetings for purpose of electing the new Chairman.
問呢個？
係。
我公司。
嗯。
即係你誒。
追究嘅。
businesses.
啊！我哋打緊先，打緊先得啦～
has the responsibility.
and authority to deal with the problems.
especially transacting the urgent or essential.
Both the secretary and outside senior council are of the view that.
cause by the inordinate delay in the election of the chairman.
as the peasant in the peasant situation, the incumbent Housecom chairman, the honourable Starry Lee.
and make sure that there is no undue disruption to the work of Housecom and its normal or proper functioning.
Therefore, in the present situation, the incumbent House Com Chairmen, the honourable Starry, has both responsibilities and authority to deal with House Com's heavy backlog of work.
just.
比較有責。
election.
去處理。
So what what do you mean urgent letters?
畀曬來回。
嗱，第一樣嘢咧就係誒。
六個月內都未選到主席。
十幾號嘅事啊，發生咗啦，但係我係冇。
我參加法律議員之前嘅嘛，咁所以係冇問到依個問題。
啊，當然好明顯咧，就係現任嘅內會主席係有權。
各委員噉就等內會去尋求，自己去尋求一個解決方法。
問題暫時嘅問題，噉我亦都係頭先講咗，我就會將所有嘅法律意見。
我問嘅誒法律意見咧，係去尋求點樣去解決內會依個誒？
積下嚟嘅緊急事項，咁所以依個就係要內會去處理，因為我講咗畀你，我係三月尾已經開始尋找法律意見，咁四月。
Sort of larger matters should Starry be tackling? Are you talking about things like the national anthem law? And then second question being, are you saying basically that Starry should assume as chairman?
你 know。
是。
四。
sorry。
We have.
fourteen。
Apart from.
因為Flashpoint將要 wrap up in。
但，after six months。
Also, what sorts of powers?
In a prudent manner.
need to exercise her power.
The election is. Is are you saying that the election is not going to happen?
is still the incumbent House Chairman.
It's very simple. I did not.
From the new legal advisory update, what sort of powers does Starry have? Can you elaborate?
但係。
資產份。
就啲散。
bills.
零一等等。
依家即係根據。
翁，咩？
啊！誒。
Is that urgent?
嘅意見同埋你決定之後咧，李慧瓊係咪可以決定喺？
I think it was up to members and the public.
And we also have the appointment of chief chief justice. The resolution there.
Housecom， and another twenty something， you know， subsidiary legislation there。
我問你，你
I haven't I haven't say anything. It'll be up to the Housecom to decide how they handle.
also，we have missed the chance of looking scrutinise over a hundred subsidiary legislation.
係。
定嗰個議程。
主席嘅特別。
李慧瓊可能會。
擔唔擔心，即係。
嘅決定會唔會擔心佢？
之後係可以處理平時內。
之外，係咪可以展開另一個門檻？
做到一啲百缺嘅挑戰咧。誒。
第二就係誒，除咗李慧如，除咗決定召開特別。
知深大藏嘅意見係清晰嘅。
噉我亦都畀咗內會咁多位成員啦。
平時內會處理嘅線路咧，咁會唔會擔心就係衍生咗另一個箱包區嘅話？
另外就係啱誒嗰個法律文件都提到，就係誒現任嘅內管處長可能有機會濫用嘅。
咁點樣去處理咧？我相信佢哋有集體嘅智慧去解決現時呢一個誒。
處理嘅選舉問題，或者係我哋有緊急嘅事係要做嘅問題，誒等等嘅咧，佢哋應該係誒用佢嘅正常方法應該處理到。
誒。
但係話選選。
嗯。
取消計劃又話。
未消決完就係呢一個就。
就在於可以另外整一個會議要。
我想問翻嚟就點樣定義緊急事項係由你為？
如果你留頭先留心聽咧。
我就想問下咧，頭先頭咁講法啦，即係話其實而家李慧瓊嗰個。
你內會嘅時候係咪意味住內會嗰個選主席嘅程序會各自？
另外就想問翻就係噉，如果噉嘅情況下，噉佢要召開另一場會議。
立法會嘅意見當然係一個普通嘅情況裏邊。
誒，內會點樣去行使個權力？點樣去處理個選舉，同埋點樣？
誒內會主席去運用嘅權力，召開會議去處理啊啲緊急事項咧，噉我覺得都係由內會佢自己去啊決定。
去解釋啦，咁但係過咗六個月，依個情況就當然唔係普通啦。咁所以點解我哋去尋求一個法律意見，去睇睇有咩辦法可以解決現時嘅？
難題啊！如果係普通嘅就已經冇事啦，已經選咗主席啦噉樣。咁所以個問題出現就係依六個月嘅啊拉布或者六個月嘅啊個主持人嘅。
係。
比食貨。
嗯。
但。
係咪？
你之前都係講。
呃，The prudence.
If you look at the ROP.
In calling meetings.
Starry is still the incumbent.
誒，the election of the new chairman is important.
now after one week, two week, a month or two months, she can still exercise.
But if it is after six months, and you have a lot of urgent businesses.
I think the important thing is that under normal circumstances.
個表現咧係令到誒我係需要尋求外界嘅法律意見，去睇下有咩方法去解決現時嘅困局。
怕。
公司入。
貨。
under that.
好嘛，OK，唔該曬。
Jointly advise, affirm.
The senior councils.
look at, there are so many bills.
並不是一個執法嘅部門。
technical，啊，to。
that she have that power to do it.
Could she exercise her power?
So many other issues that we need to look at, then.
所以你 can call a meeting to look at urgent businesses for the household.
依個唔係喺我問我哋嘅法律嘅意見啊之中，咁究竟佢依個點樣咧？噉你要問問執法部門誒點樣去處理啦，因為我。